<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mingwei Gu</title>
    <link>https://mingwei.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mingwei Gu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 12:21:45 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mingwei.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>No Vacancy: Part One</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/no-vacancy-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 12:21:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/no-vacancy-part-one/</guid>
      <description>The following is a story snippet based on a prompt from this MasterClass article.
Father Thomas hobbled down the stone path back from the graveyard. The young priest in his thirties leaned into his aluminum walking cane. He pressed down with both hands, desperately trying to open the distance between him and his pursuer.
Thomas craned his neck over his shoulder for a moment. The moonlight outlined Francine’s ghastly figure fifteen feet away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Science Fiction</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/writing-sci-fi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 18:28:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/writing-sci-fi/</guid>
      <description>Why the flurry of posts recently? Well, I’m dusting off an old dream: to write science fiction. And the blog posts are a way to get me writing again.
I liked writing in high school and college. Seeing my ideas escape through my fingertips and materialize on screen made me feel so alive. Especially after taking forever to turn those ideas over and over again in my mind with a deadline approaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Meditation on a Cough</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/meditation-cough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 17:26:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/meditation-cough/</guid>
      <description>Seven days in silence. No electronics, no miming, no eye contact. No reading, no writing. Meditating while sitting, meditating while walking. Eating, sleeping. The bare necessities.
It was the afternoon on day four of my first week-long meditation retreat. More than halfway through. I just wanted to make it to the end and not go crazy.
I entered the meditation hall. Formerly a chapel, it was an open space with wooden flooring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How role-playing can level up your team at work</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/role-playing-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 19:03:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/role-playing-at-work/</guid>
      <description>My friend recently started hosting a weekly Dungeons and Dragons (D&amp;amp;D) game. As the Game Master (or Dungeon Master), he has to prepare scenarios each week, he has to improvise to react to what we players do, and of course he has to keep us players entertained and challenged.
I’m starting to think those same Game Master skills would make someone great at organizing and running employee training games. And it&amp;rsquo;d be way more engaging as a new employee to have more training games to replace lectures, readings, or ad-hoc learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I learned about Rocky Horror in fourth grade</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/rocky-horror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:48:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/rocky-horror/</guid>
      <description>I’m a millennial. Most of my generation learned about 70s American culture from parents or older relatives.
Me, I’m a child of immigrants. And I grew up a quintessential geek. So naturally what I learned about the 70s came from the internet.
Case in point, I learned about the Rocky Horror Picture Show in an online RPG, Barren Realms.
What’s a MUD? Like most RPGs, Barren Realms asks you to create a fantasy-themed character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I’m Mingwei Gu, and this is my personal website and blog.
I spent eight years at YipitData, a data-driven investment research firm in NYC. When I left, I was leading a multi-disciplinary engineering team developing tools and platforms for internal data analyst teams.
Before that, I briefly worked in derivatives trading. And before that, I graduated from MIT with a degree in math with computer science.
Currently, I’m exploring product ideas in the data engineering and analytics space.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
