<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mingwei Gu</title>
    <link>https://mingwei.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mingwei Gu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 18:54:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mingwei.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Graffiti Chase</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/graffiti-chase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 18:54:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/graffiti-chase/</guid>
      <description>“Stop where you are! Police!”
The cop was a few houses down and running over. I tossed my molecular spray paint can into some bushes and booked it.
I thought about finishing my art. You know when you’re in the zone and not even a dropby shooting can get you out of it? Well, I was just about there.
But if a kid like me gets caught tagging in this ritzy neighborhood, I’m done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Broke</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/data-broke/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 18:59:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/data-broke/</guid>
      <description>Greg ran his fingers over the smooth glass display case. His eyes darted from one data crystal to another, and preview info displayed on his optical feed. This shop was known for carrying the most selective audience segments.
Greg was on shaky ground with his wife Belinda. Her birthday was coming up soon, and he hoped a spectacular birthday present would get him out of trouble. And he wanted to get her a top-of-the-line data crystal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Muffin</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/hot-muffin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 23:02:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/hot-muffin/</guid>
      <description>Veena fills the last muffin cup with batter. Halfway through the morning’s prep. She opens the commercial oven, and puts the tin of thirty muffins inside. As she closes the oven door, she wipes her brow with her forearm.
Working in a bakery has been the most fun she’s had in witness protection. But sometimes, she wishes she could get back to the action.
Veena’s dressed in a white pastry chef hat and a white apron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floating Dreams</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/floating-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 23:40:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/floating-dreams/</guid>
      <description>The mark just had to run off and hide in an asteroid belt. Braun flips on the long range scanners and leans back in his pilot’s seat. His scout ship Mercurial drifts toward the asteroid through the darkness of space.
I need to capture this bounty. I’ll finally have enough to buy my freedom.
Braun looks at a bracer on his left forearm. Engraved on it are the letters BD2948. A tear balances on the rim of his eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skewered</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/skewered/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 23:59:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/skewered/</guid>
      <description>Ghentan inches his katana out from its sheath.
The cherry blossom trees around him creak as a calm breeze comes through the narrow mountain pass. The moonlight behind him gleams off the short swords of the three ninjas in front.
Father will be executed if I do not reach him by dawn. And these ninja goons aren’t going to stop me.
Ghentan rushes to the closest ninja. His wooden sandals clack against the rocky pass with every step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost and Found</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/lost-and-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 18:56:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/lost-and-found/</guid>
      <description>The cargo container slips from his Crab Mecha’s grasp.
It goes tumbling away from the quiet grey loading bay of the orbital trading station and toward the lush green planet below. Dillon grits his teeth and extends the Mecha’s arms to recover the cargo, but he misses and manages to send it flying away even faster.
Dillon cannot lose this cargo. Or else he’ll get dragged into a planet side recovery mission and miss leave to meet his newborn daughter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Mildew</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/no-mildew/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 22:11:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/no-mildew/</guid>
      <description>The scents of lavender and spring rush past as Lori opens the door to her freshly cleaned apartment.
She discards her suitcase and purse by the door and kicks off her flats in the direction of the shoerack. It’s been a long week on-site at the client’s office, and all she wants is to lie in her bathtub and drink some wine.
All I do is work, she thinks. And the client keeps asking for more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Speed Asteroid Chase</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/high-speed-asteroid-chase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 17:51:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/high-speed-asteroid-chase/</guid>
      <description>“That bastard’s got my grandson. I can’t let him get away.” Paolo mutters under his breath.
He’s clipped onto the back of a small asteroid. And the kidnapper’s on an even smaller one about half a kilometer in front.
And both asteroids are hurtling towards Earth. Through the blackness of space.
Paolo’s wearing a standard atmospheric suit made of curved bronze metal plates. Based on a diving suit design from 1882, its semi-spherical joints fit together to form airtight seals and give him a limited range of motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Vacancy: Part Two</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/no-vacancy-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 13:55:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/no-vacancy-part-two/</guid>
      <description>“Yes, you’re dead. Welcome to Central Processing. Please wait for your number to be called”
I woke up and saw the large, butcher paper banner.
It was hand-written in heavy, black marker. Except for the message, it wouldn’t have been out of place at my granddaughter’s high school pep rallies.
In my right hand, I had a paper slip with the numbers “A0F35B1 - Francine”
I was sitting in a grey, plastic folding chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pie in the Face</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/pie-in-the-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 14:20:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/pie-in-the-face/</guid>
      <description>The lemon merengue pie sailed through the air and splattered on his face.
Lenny sat motionless on stage in the school auditorium. One camera clicked and flashed. He leaned forward slowly and gently removed the pie tin, catching the largest pie chunks. Another camera. He placed the tin on the table besides him and grabbed a few paper towels.
He stood up and wiped the pie from his face. Lenny was in his late twenties and a new sixth grade math teacher at Los Tranquilos Middle School.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About Dignity</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/all-about-dignity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 13:31:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/all-about-dignity/</guid>
      <description>All he cared about was his dignity. Even at the cost of his soul.
Jim’s daughters had said that about him many years ago. It had hurt to hear, but he had nothing to say in return.
He was thinking about that conversation as he stood on the curb next to his taxicab. His shift was almost done, and he was taking a much needed break.
A man in his fifties, Jim was dressed in pressed tan khakis and a green zipped pullover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Vacancy: Part One</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/stories/no-vacancy-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 12:21:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/stories/no-vacancy-part-one/</guid>
      <description>The following is a story snippet based on a prompt from this MasterClass article.
Father Thomas hobbled down the stone path back from the graveyard. The young priest in his thirties leaned into his aluminum walking cane. He pressed down with both hands, desperately trying to open the distance between him and his pursuer.
Thomas craned his neck over his shoulder for a moment. The moonlight outlined Francine’s ghastly figure fifteen feet away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Science Fiction</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/writing-sci-fi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 18:28:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/writing-sci-fi/</guid>
      <description>Why the flurry of posts recently? Well, I’m dusting off an old dream: to write science fiction. And the blog posts are a way to get me writing again.
I liked writing in high school and college. Seeing my ideas escape through my fingertips and materialize on screen made me feel so alive. Especially after taking forever to turn those ideas over and over again in my mind with a deadline approaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Meditation on a Cough</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/meditation-cough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 17:26:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/meditation-cough/</guid>
      <description>Seven days in silence. No electronics, no miming, no eye contact. No reading, no writing. Meditating while sitting, meditating while walking. Eating, sleeping. The bare necessities.
It was the afternoon on day four of my first week-long meditation retreat. More than halfway through. I just wanted to make it to the end and not go crazy.
I entered the meditation hall. Formerly a chapel, it was an open space with wooden flooring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How role-playing can level up your team at work</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/role-playing-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 19:03:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/role-playing-at-work/</guid>
      <description>My friend recently started hosting a weekly Dungeons and Dragons (D&amp;amp;D) game. As the Game Master (or Dungeon Master), he has to prepare scenarios each week, he has to improvise to react to what we players do, and of course he has to keep us players entertained and challenged.
I’m starting to think those same Game Master skills would make someone great at organizing and running employee training games. And it&amp;rsquo;d be way more engaging as a new employee to have more training games to replace lectures, readings, or ad-hoc learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I learned about Rocky Horror in fourth grade</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/rocky-horror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:48:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/rocky-horror/</guid>
      <description>I’m a millennial. Most of my generation learned about 70s American culture from parents or older relatives.
Me, I’m a child of immigrants. And I grew up a quintessential geek. So naturally what I learned about the 70s came from the internet.
Case in point, I learned about the Rocky Horror Picture Show in an online RPG, Barren Realms.
What’s a MUD? Like most RPGs, Barren Realms asks you to create a fantasy-themed character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I’m Mingwei Gu, and this is my personal website and blog.
I spent eight years at YipitData, a data-driven investment research firm in NYC. When I left, I was leading a multi-disciplinary engineering team developing tools and platforms for internal data analyst teams.
Before that, I briefly worked in derivatives trading. And before that, I graduated from MIT with a degree in math with computer science.
Currently, I’m exploring product ideas in the data engineering and analytics space.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
