<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mingwei Gu</title>
    <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mingwei Gu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 10:25:59 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mingwei.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 Self Limiting Questions</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/4-self-limiting-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 10:25:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/4-self-limiting-questions/</guid>
      <description>For far too long, I&amp;rsquo;ve had trouble getting through creative work without interruption. Specifically, in the middle of work I&amp;rsquo;m doing, I&amp;rsquo;d think about the appropriate level of quality. About whether it&amp;rsquo;ll be successful. About what it means for my identity. And to my future.
My mind goes wandering. And I want to do anything but do the actual task at hand. I&amp;rsquo;d go on social media or check my email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Science Fiction</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/writing-sci-fi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 18:28:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/writing-sci-fi/</guid>
      <description>Why the flurry of posts recently? Well, I’m dusting off an old dream: to write science fiction. And the blog posts are a way to get me writing again.
I liked writing in high school and college. Seeing my ideas escape through my fingertips and materialize on screen made me feel so alive. Especially after taking forever to turn those ideas over and over again in my mind with a deadline approaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Meditation on a Cough</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/meditation-cough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 17:26:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/meditation-cough/</guid>
      <description>Seven days in silence. No electronics, no miming, no eye contact. No reading, no writing. Meditating while sitting, meditating while walking. Eating, sleeping. The bare necessities.
It was the afternoon on day four of my first week-long meditation retreat. More than halfway through. I just wanted to make it to the end and not go crazy.
I entered the meditation hall. Formerly a chapel, it was an open space with wooden flooring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How role-playing can level up your team at work</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/role-playing-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 19:03:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/role-playing-at-work/</guid>
      <description>My friend recently started hosting a weekly Dungeons and Dragons (D&amp;amp;D) game. As the Game Master (or Dungeon Master), he has to prepare scenarios each week, he has to improvise to react to what we players do, and of course he has to keep us players entertained and challenged.
I’m starting to think those same Game Master skills would make someone great at organizing and running employee training games. And it&amp;rsquo;d be way more engaging as a new employee to have more training games to replace lectures, readings, or ad-hoc learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I learned about Rocky Horror in fourth grade</title>
      <link>https://mingwei.me/posts/rocky-horror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:48:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingwei.me/posts/rocky-horror/</guid>
      <description>I’m a millennial. Most of my generation learned about 70s American culture from parents or older relatives.
Me, I’m a child of immigrants. And I grew up a quintessential geek. So naturally what I learned about the 70s came from the internet.
Case in point, I learned about the Rocky Horror Picture Show in an online RPG, Barren Realms.
What’s a MUD? Like most RPGs, Barren Realms asks you to create a fantasy-themed character.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
